data driven documents or d3 is a javascript library for creating
数据驱动文档或 d3 是一个javascript 库，用于创建
interactive data visualizations with scalable vector graphics if you've ever
具有可缩放矢量图形的交互式数据可视化，如果您
been to a website that has a graph map scatter plot histogram dependency
曾经访问过具有图表的网站散点图 直方图 依赖
diagram b swarm tree map or pie chart it's probably powered by d3 under the
图 b 群树图或饼图它可能由 d3 提供支持
hood it was created in 2011 with the goal of generating svg graphics from
它创建于 2011 年，目的是从数据中生成 svg 图形
data drawing a data visualization by hand is extremely difficult with d3 you
手动绘制数据可视化对于 d3 来说非常困难，您
start with some input data then write some javascript to programmatically draw
从一些输入数据开始，然后编写一些 javascript 以编程方式
the graphic for you which can then be made interactive with things like labels
为您绘制图形，然后可以进行交互 使用标签
and controls and when the underlying data changes it can interpolate and
和控件之类的东西，当底层数据发生变化时，它可以
animate between values resulting in a beautiful visual for the end user that's
在值之间进行插值和动画处理，从而为最终用户提供漂亮的视觉效果，
built entirely on web standards that you already know like html css and
完全建立在您已经知道的 web 标准（如 html css 和
javascript its api allows you to select and manipulate items in the dom not much
javascript）上，它的 api 允许您选择和 在 dom 中操作项目
different than something like jquery what makes d3 different is that you can
与 jquery 之类的操作没有太大区别 d3 的不同之处在于 y 您可以
set properties as functions that automatically draw different graphics
将属性设置为
based on your data to get started you'll first want to grab an element from the
根据您的数据自动绘制不同图形的函数以开始使用您首先要使用 select 方法从 dom 中获取一个元素，
dom with the select method like an empty svg you could then draw a single shape
例如一个空的svg，然后您可以在其中绘制单个形状
inside of it with the append method and customize its appearance by chaining the
append 方法并通过将绘制单个形状的属性方法链接到它来自定义其外观，
attribute method to it that draws a single shape but the real power of d3
但是
comes into play when you attach data to a selection instead of using a for loop
当您将数据附加到选择而不是使用 for 循环
to draw a bunch of shapes the select all method allows you to describe how to
来绘制一堆形状时，d3 的真正威力就会发挥作用 select all方法 允许您描述如何
draw shape making your code more declarative you can then attach data to
绘制形状，使您的代码更具声明性，然后您可以
it in the form of an array or an external file and it will draw a shape
以数组或外部文件的形式将数据附加到它，它将
for every point in your data set each point has three possible states enter
为数据集中的每个点绘制一个形状每个点都有三种可能的状态输入
update and exit enter is when you would initially draw your shape but d3 also
更新和退出输入是您最初绘制形状的时候，但 d3 还
keeps track of changes to the data set allowing you to react when data is
跟踪数据集的更改，允许您在数据
updated or removed it also provides a bunch of features to make your data look
更新或删除时做出反应，它还提供了一堆 fea 使您的数据看起来很
beautiful like helpers that automatically draw scales along the x
漂亮的助手，可以
and y axis based on the domain and range of the data or you might use transition
根据数据的域和范围自动沿 x 和 y 轴绘制比例尺，或者您可以
to create an animation as each data point is added to the chart and finally
在将每个数据点添加到图表时使用转换来创建动画，最后
you might listen to events to add tooltips or other interactive elements
您可以 收听事件以将工具提示或其他交互式元素添加
to your chart this has been d3js in 100 seconds if you want to see more short
到您的图表中这已经是 100秒内的 d3js 如果您想看到更多这样的短
videos like this hit the like button and subscribe and if you want to go beyond
视频，请点击喜欢按钮并订阅，如果您想超过
100 seconds there's a new fireship pro lesson about building a real-time chart
100 秒，那么有一个新的 fireship pro关于使用 d3 和 firestore 构建实时图表的课程
with d3 and firestore thanks for watching and i will see you in the next
感谢您的观看，我们下节再见
one